Nithin Baby Solution Architect +1 425 758 8249 / +91 8891578366

• 9+ years of experience in development of Java & Scala based web applications, standalone and RESTful micro-services

 Extensive experience in software development activities comprising requirement analysis, design, estimation, coding, implementation, code review, testing, user training and enhancements.



• Experience working for the leading companies in the Travel and hospitality industries, where scalability and performance are crucial.

Skill Set Summary

- Elicitation/requirement gathering, analysis, designing, planning, and solution feasibility analysis.
- Exceptional skill set in understanding different business flows and implementing new features.
- Excellent at managing stakeholder relationships; recommending needs, consolidating and communicating requirements.

Technology	Details
Programming Languages	Java, Scala, Python
Frameworks	Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Scalatra
Web Technologies	HTML, JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, JSP
Testing	Scalatest, Selenium
Version Control Systems	Git, Svn
Cloud technologies	AWS S3, EC2, ECS, SQS, SNS, MSK, Lambda etc.
Dependency Management	Maven, Gradle
Other tools and platforms	Cordova, Node JS, Node Webkit, Kafka, Docker
Database	MySQL
IDE	IntelliJ, Eclipse, VS Code

Key Achievements

- Achieved Best Debutant award (2018) and Excellence award (2021) for the outstanding performance in IBS.
- Played a key role in releasing partner central V3 application for supplier inventory management and delivering new features like self-service promotion tool, user management, booking questions, option groups etc.
- Participated in IATA NDC International Hackathon (2018) as part of Expedia team and competed against about 30 teams from different parts of world and bagged runners up prize.
- Rolled out DBO App V2, a multi-platform application for the business team to showcase the Estimation, optimization, automation, other capabilities and improve the outcome of

- projects in terms of time, cost etc. I was a key team member in requirement gathering and implementation. Received Digital Superstar award for the performance in the project.
- Developed a new responsive web design for MSI(Multi Service Integration) team of Cognizant. Also received Excellence Award from Cognizant for the performance in the project.
- Rolled out localization of activities to new locales, bringing additional revenue in millions. Received appreciation/shoutouts from stakeholders for the same.

Educational Background

Institution	Course	Duration	CGPA/Grade /Percentage
Rajagiri School of	B. Tech in Electronics and	June, 2010-June	8.09
Engineering & Technology	Communication	2014	
Silver Hills HSS	Plus Two	June, 2008-May	97.67%
		2010	
Silver Hills HSS	SSLC	June, 2007-May 2008	Full A+

Professional Experience

Company: IBS Software(2017-Current)Address: 400 Galleria Parkway, Suite 1750,

Atlanta, Georgia 30339

United States

Project Name	Activities connectivity (Expedia)
Project Description	Fetch activities inventory from different partners and third-party companies. Build backend applications to import pricing, availability etc. from partners by connecting through APIs
Business Domain	Travel & Hospitality
Duration	Current Project (Feb 2023 – present)
Technology	Java, Scala, Spring Boot, MySQL
Role in Project	Software Developer
	 Performed coding and unit testing Provided production support Collaborate with clients to find possible solutions for the new requirements. Design and implementation of new features in the application.

Resume

Project Name	Activities localization (Expedia)
Project Description	Activities contents ingested in English are translated to other languages using internal APIs, AWS and other tools
Business Domain	Travel & Hospitality
Duration	1 Years (Jan 2022 – Jan 2023)
Technology	Java, MySQL, Python, Jenkins, AWS
Role in Project	Software Developer
	Requirement gathering, design and development

Project Name	Domain modernization (Expedia)
Project Description	This project was aimed at modernizing activities supply system, thereby support new features like AI based sorting, tagging, optimized pricing and content structure, improved efficiency etc.
Business Domain	Travel & Hospitality
Duration	1.5 Years (Aug 2020 – Jan 2022)
Technology	Scala, Java, Spring Boot, MySQL, Python, Jenkins, AWS, React JS
Role in Project	Full stack developer
	 Create Restful APIs to support new domain. Update front-end application to consume new APIs

Project Name	SSO integration (Expedia)
Project Description	Integrate SSO login mechanism with help of Expedia internal OIDC based auth system.
Business Domain	Travel & Hospitality
Duration	.5 Years (April 2020 – Aug 2020)
Technology	Scala, React JS
Role in Project	Full stack developer

• Update existing authentication framework to support OIDC/JWT at both front-end and back-end applications.

Project Name	Promotions (Expedia)
Project Description	Add new feature to support promotions/marketing for activities business.
Business Domain	Travel & Hospitality
Duration	1.5 years (Jan 2019 – April 2020)
Technology	Java, Spring, Scala, React JS, JSP
Role in Project	Full stack developer
	 Design and development of new Restful APIs to support promotions Create UI pages in partner portal for promotion CRUD operations Update Expedia shopping and booking layers to support promotions

Project Name	Partner Central (Expedia)
Project Description	Migrate old partner portal tool to newer version, by allowing suppliers to manage inventory themselves. Migrated existing features to new application and added newer features like Booking Questions, Bulk Update etc.
Business Domain	Travel & Hospitality
Duration	2.5 years (August 2017 – Dec 2019)
Technology	Scala, Java, MySQL, Angular JS, React JS
Role in Project	Full stack Developer
	 Collaborate with clients to find possible solutions for the new requirements. Migrate existing features. Add new Rest APIs and UI pages Design and implementation of new features in the application. Addition of unit tests and end-to-end automation tests for ensuring the stability of the application. Primary point of contact for tasks related to partner central – inventory management tool.

Company: Cognizant Technology Solutions (July 1st, 2014 – July 20th, 2017)

Address: Plot No. 1, Cochin Special Economic Zone, 3rd floor, Technopolis Kakkanad, Kochi, Kerala, India, PIN: 682037

Project Name	DBO (Delivering Business Outcome)
Project Description	DBO app is a product of Cognizant which helps the clients in identifying the areas where they can improve the outcome of projects in terms of time, cost etc. The app showcases various opportunities of optimization depending on the industry selected and pipelines associated with it. It also graphically represents the advantage gained on implementing different processes like automation and standardization. The app uses web technologies and using single code base it is made available in Web, Desktop, Android and iPad platforms.
Business Domain	Business Development
Duration	1 year and 7 months (January 2016 – July 2017)
Technology	Java, Angular JS, HTML, Cordova, Node Webkit
Role in Project	Full stack developer
	 Collaborate with business team to find possible solutions for the new requirements. Development of new pages as per the requirement shared by business team/ visual designer and implementing the front-end functionalities. Integrating with the backend team for creation of web services. Timely completion of development and fixing of bugs.

Project Name	MSI-CoE (Multi Service Integration-Centre of Excellence)
Project Description	MSI-CoE is a team in Cognizant which creates tools to handle very large projects. Worked single handed for various front-end requirements in the project.
Business Domain	Cognizant Internal Application
Duration	6 months (July 2015 – December 2015)
Technology	Angular JS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Cordova, Node Webkit

Project Name	NLG Mobile App
Project Description	Cordova based Hybrid Mobile App for US Insurance company National Life Group for their agents to login and view the policies and commissions linked with them. Some of the new features include Finger Print based access, down-line agent view for up-line managers.
Business Domain	Insurance
Duration	6 months (January 2015 to June 2015)
Technology	Android, iOS, Java, JavaScript
Role in Project	Hybrid Mobile Application Developer
	 Development of new pages and modification of existing pages as per the requirement shared by Client. Implementation of touch ID based authentication and other new features

Designing of webpages for One-MSI and MSI-CoE landing pages. Responsive web designing for BO Composer, a web based tool

Creating a common dashboard template for MSI which displays

various outcomes graphically using charts and graphs.

Web Developer

created by MSI.

28-February-2024 Seattle, WA, USA

Role in Project